Curriculum Vitae (CV) for Eng. Timothy Musiomi Musembe

Name: Eng. Timothy Musiomi Musembe

Profession: Civil/Structural Engineer

Date of Birth: 22nd July, 1979

Nationality: Kenyan

Contacts:

P.O.Box 22483-00400 Nairobi

Phone:(mobile) 0724 675 559/0735 525 225

Email; musiomi2005@gmail.com, musiomi2005@yahoo.com

Membership of Professional Bodies/Societies

- Registered with the Engineers Board of Kenya as a Consulting Engineer (EBK No. E376)
- Registered with the Engineers Board of Kenya as a Registered/Professional Engineer (EBK No. A2552)
- Licensed Consulting Civil Engineer (EBK)
- Corporate Member of Institution of Engineers of Kenya
- Member American Concrete Institute (MACI)
- Member International Association of Bridge and Structural Engineering (MIABSE)
- Registered EIA/EA Expert (National Environmental Management Authority-Kenya)

Detailed Tasks Assigned

- Project coordination
- Project feasibility studies
- Engineering planning and design
- Engineering detailing and documentation
- Site supervision and inspections
- Structural audits, assessments and surveys

Quality Control

Key Qualifications

Eng. Musiomi is a Registered Consulting Engineer with a vast professional experience in engineering training, design and practice. He has vast experience in structural and civil engineering projects and has been involved in the design and supervision of buildings and civil engineering works, water retaining structures, culverts etc. After graduation he gained his initial experience in site supervision and coordination.

Eng. Musiomi is a holder of Master of Science degree in civil engineering (structures option), which has enabled him to assume full responsibility for the design, supervision and successful completion of several challenging projects.

In addition, he has gained useful experience in teaching undergraduate and postgraduate students. He has been involved in the supervision of final year students' projects. He is currently, together with others, supervising postgraduate students at SMARTEC-JKUAT taking MSc in Construction Engineering and Management.

He has worked in a variety of projects including Renewable Energy, Commercial, Housing, Parking, Banking, office blocks, Educational, Medical and Religious Facilities.

Education

- Shieywe Secondary School (1995-1998)
- Jomo Kenyatta University of Agric. and Techn. B.Sc.Civil Eng.Hons. (2000-2005)
- Jomo Kenyatta University of Agric. and Techn. MSc. Civil Eng (2006-2010)
- IEET JKUAT Cert. in Environmental Impact Assessment & Environmental Audit (2011)

Employment History

2018 - To date : Managing Director-Muscon Consulting & Engineering Co. Ltd

2015 - To date : Director/Chief Engineer-Precise Material Testing Ltd

2011 – To date : Lecturer-Multimedia University of Kenya

2010 – 2018 : Principal Engineer-Civil Engineering Consultancy Ltd

2012 – 2016 : Consultant – Baseplan Associates Ltd

2006 – 2011 : Teaching Assistant/Assistant Lecturer JKUAT

2010 – 2012 : Projects Engineer – Baseplan Associates Ltd

2005 – 2010 : Assistant Engineer – Baseplan Associates Ltd

2005 – 2005 : Assistant projects co-ordinator – Ramani Enterprises

Engineering consultancy experience/Sample projects

Civil/Structural Engineering Projects (Design and Supervision)

- 1. NACHU Plaza in Upper Hill; Structural design of an eighteen (18) storey office block with three basements (the project in on-going).
- 2. KCB Towers in Upper Hill; Design, design review of specialist works and overall site supervision of a twenty five (25) storey plus five (5) basements reinforced concrete building.
- 3. Rings View apartments in Kileleshwa, Nairobi (two number blocks of eight storeys each)
- 4. Proposed residential apartments in Kizingo, Mombasa for ICDC (an eleven storey apartment block with one basement)
- 5. Proposed Namanisho Park in Matasia (50 number town houses and associated civil works).
- 6. Proposed Willow Park Project comprising of eight number three storey apartment blocks in Banana, Nairobi
- 7. Proposed Achelis Center Mombasa Road comprising of workshops, godowns and an eight storey office block.
- 8. Proposed Gitanga Close Duplex (a twelve storey residential duplexed block along Gitanga Close)
- Proposed Eldama Ravine Duplex (a twelve storey residential duplexed block along Eldama Ravine road in Nairobi)
- 10. Proposed solar power plant in Kericho for Solar Steam
- 11. Mixed development in Embu. The project involves the design and supervision of a number of facilities in Embu. The facilities include: aircraft hangar, operations office block, catering unit, residential apartments, taxi ways and other road works, storm water and foul water drainage system (we were the lead consultants in this project).
- 12. Proposed infrastructural development in Meru University of Science and Technology (Access and circulation road networks, foul water reticulation system, waste stabilisation ponds, water supply reticulation and storage system, sports fields).
- 13. Proposed engineering workshops and laboratory in Meru University of Science and Technology (structural portal frames in structural steel work and RC concrete).
- 14. Lone view residential estate along Mombasa Road. The project involve putting up 60 maisonettes and 240 apartments (24 apartment blocks)-Design of structures, water reticulation and access road network.
- 15. KPLC sub-station in Bomet (structural design of foundations and equipment support steel structures: drainage and road work design of the site)

- 16. Extension of KPLC sub-station in Rabai (structural design review for equipment support steel structures)
- 17. Proposed CDM hotel in Meru. This is a twenty four storey five star hotel with deep basement (four levels). Preliminary design is complete.
- 18. Engineering workshops for Meru University of Science and Technology
- 19. Serene Valley Apartments- The project involve putting up two nine storey apartment blocks in Upper Hill along Kiambere Road. The superstructures are supported on a variety of foundation types ranging from isolated footings to cellular rafts due to highly variable ground conditions. The structural frames are almost complete.
- 20. Housing scheme for KPLC pension fund in Runda (Nairobi). A housing scheme comprising of 39 country homes and a community club house. The project is complete.
- 21. Proposed skyline hotel in Arusha Tanzania. This is a twenty four storey five star hotel with deep basement (four levels). Design is complete and the project is at the tender stage.
- 22. High rise office block in Kilimani for K-Rep Bank. K-Rep Bank Office block is an eight storey building with a sub-basement. My duties on the project involved carrying out engineering design, supervision of drafting, and supervision of construction on site. The project was completed in 2008.
- 23. Multistorey apartment block in Kilimani for K-Rep Bank. This is a five storey (originally planned and designed to be an eight storey building) apartment block in Kilimani.
- 24. Helstrom student centre- Multipurpose complex for Africa Nazarene University. Planned as a landmark of Africa Nazarene University, Helstrom student centre houses a variety of functions ranging from offices, lecture halls, auditoriums and indoor games.

Structural Audit/Appraisal/Forensic Structural Engineering Projects

- 1. Forensic investigation of collapsed building in Lower Kabete
- 2. Forensic investigation of collapsed building in Ndenderu, Kiambu County
- 3. Forensic investigation of collapsed building in Thika, Kiambu County
- 4. Structural appraisal of tilted/settled building in Gacharage, Kiambu County
- 5. Structural audit of the existing Sarit Centre in Westlands, Nairobi
- 6. Structural audit of the existing Garden City Mall, Nairobi
- 7. Structural audit of existing commercial development along Kenyatta Avenue in Nairobi
- 8. Structural audit of a fourteen storey Renaissance Corporate Park along Elgon Road in Upper Hill in Nairobi
- 9. Structural audit of the existing Jumuia Hospital in Kaimosi, Vihiga County
- 10. Structural audit of existing godowns/warehouses for Chandaria Industries in Nairobi
- 11. Structural audit of 3 no apartment blocks in Imara Daima Estate in Nairobi
- 12. Structural audit/appraisal of damaged UN offices in Mogadishu, Somalia
- 13. Structural audit of damaged Serare School in Ngong

Quality Control & Assurance and Geotechnical Investigation Projects

- 1. Proposed Pinnacle Towers in Upper Hill [Quality control and quality assurance]
- 2. Proposed phase III Sarit Centre [Quality control and quality assurance including detailed geotechnical investigation]
- 3. Proposed AVIC Headquarters next to Kempisky Hotel along Chiromo Road [Site sampling of materials, laboratory testing of the samples]
- 4. Proposed Water Front Mall in Karen [Site sampling of materials, laboratory testing of the samples]
- 5. Proposed 400kv transmission line Loyangalani-Suswa [Geotechnical investigation, concrete mix design, site sampling of materials, laboratory testing of the samples. In situ quality control tests on compacted soils, non-destructive testing of concrete]
- 6. Geotechnical investigation for the proposed Wadi Degla Sports Club in Karen
- 7. Skyview Mall in Thika [Geotechnical investigation, site sampling of materials, laboratory testing of the samples (3 number boreholes up to 30m deep)]
- 8. Proposed Ngandu Plaza Racecourse Nairobi [Geotechnical investigation, site sampling of materials, laboratory testing of the samples]
- Proposed apartment block in Valley Arcade Nairobi A fourteen storey duplex apartment block with one number basement [Geotechnical investigation, laboratory testing of the material samples.]
- 10. Proposed Bailing shed and godowns [Site material sampling, testing and characterization.]
- 11. Proposed Thwake Dam in Makueni [Laboratory testing and characterization]
- 12. Quality control and quality assurance of proposed apartment blocks in Westlands, Nairobi

Teaching experience

Undergraduate classes

- 1. Structural analysis (static and dynamics)
- 2. Structural design
- 3. Solid mechanics
- 4. Engineering drawing
- 5. Professional ethics for engineers

Post graduate classes

- Advanced structural analysis
- 2. Advanced structural design
- 3. Finite element methods
- 4. Structural dynamics
- 5. Advanced structural materials

6. Advanced construction materials
7. Design of construction operations and support systems
8. Advanced bridge design and evaluation
Certification:
I, the undersigned, certify that these data correctly describe me, my qualifications, and my
experience.
Data
[Signature] Date:
Full name: Timothy Musiomi Musembe